Hello!
In this episode of Bug Bounty Reports Explained,
I will show you a brand new attack technique
discovered by one and only James Kettle - cient-side
desync attacks.
Specifically, I will focus on the way that
thousands of servers could be hacked that
used Akamai.
This technique gives us a variety of ways
to leak user data, and I think...
Even James himself wrote in the article that
he left a lot of bounties on the table for
us.
So watch closely!
As always, links to the sources are in the
description.
Enjoy!
This episode is sponsored by Intigriti.
Intigriti is Europe's biggest bug bounty platform
with over 400 programs to hack on.
I hugely appreciate Intigriti for investing
a lot in community enablement.
They create an awesome bug bytes newsletter,
they create monthly XSS challenges, they even
have a great YouTube channel.
If you are not one of over 50,000 hunters,
check out Intigriti now using the link from
the description.
I will start with explaining what is pipelining
in HTTP/1.
So normally, when the browser sends a request,
or when you send a request from Burp, it looks
like this: one requests, one response.
Nothing unusual.
However, you can also send two requests at
the same time and the server will give you
two responses.
Although, this is not used by browsers anymore,
it's a feature, not a bug, at least not by itself.
But how does the server differentiate between
this being two separate requests or one with
a body?
To help the server solve this problem, we
use the Content-Length header.
It tells the server, in bytes, how long our request
is.
And the server knows that, whenever the first
request is finished, the next one begins.
If you are using Burp's repeater, this header
is updated automatically.
If you try to send these two requests with
default settings, Burp will update the Content-Length
header and you will actually send one big
request.
However, if you turn that option off and set
the header to zero, the server will see two
requests and issue two responses.
Of course, if HTTP pipelining is supported.
But not every single request contains the
Content-Length header.
In fact, most of them don't because most of
requests use the get method which doesn't
contain a body.
So this header is useless because it would
always be set to zero.
And the server just doesn't expect a body
when you are requesting, let's say, a static
image.
If you manually change the method from get
to, for example, post, the servers still respond
with this static image which doesn't really
make sense to me, but it's probably to be
even more error-prone.
The fact that normally these requests don't
have a body doesn't mean you can't send one.
Let's see what happens when you do.
This is a simple image request which we can
send to a vulnerable server.
We can do the same using post method. And also,
we can use the request body, but the server
doesn't use it in any way.
And let's prepare the body of the request
so that it looks like another HTTP request.
If we send this, do you think we will get
one or two responses?
Based on what I said earlier, this is one
big request with a body of 30 bytes.
So we expect to get one response.
But this is when we get to the client-side
desync problem.
Because even though we sent the valid Content-Length
header with a value of 30, the vulnerable
server did not use this header.
It's because this endpoint never consumes
a request body, so it assumes the Content-Length
header is zero.
And it probably worked fine for years without
any problem, before James Kettle came with his new
research.
So what a vulnerable server sees is that the
first request ends here and this is a second
one, meaning it will also send two responses.
The question you should be asking yourself
now is why is that actually a problem?
Because this is not really different from
this.
And we could basically send the second version
anyway.
And that's a very good question.
But the breakthrough with client-side desync
is that with previous requests smuggling techniques,
you had to use Burp or even tools that worked
on the lower network level.
But this attack can work with the browser
because when we send this request, there is
absolutely nothing out of line.
It just happens to have the body that looks
like an HTTP request, but it's nothing invalid.
It's the server that ignores the Content-Length
header and assumes it to be zero.
You can use this to confuse the browser because
the browser wants the amount of requests to
be equal to the amount of responses.
And in this case, the browser thinks it sent
one request, but it got back two responses.
So what does it do? When it sees the next request
using the same connection,
it will respond to it with the unexpected
second response.
There's a whole variety of ways you can use
to exploit this bug.
But in this case, let's see the technique
that allowed to hack many websites built on Akamai with an XSS.
The first thing you need for this technique
to work is an endpoint that ignores the Content-Length header.
Your best candidates are static files, redirects
or different errors.
The bug was in Akamai itself, so it affected
many websites, but we'll stick to an example
of the exploit on Capital One.
If you requested a file without the trailing
slash, it redirected you to the same location
but with the trailing slash.
You could also use a post method for this.
And this is what you sent to the server to
confirm that it ignores the Content-Length
header.
There are actually three requests.
The first is the one that you want to check
if it's vulnerable to client side desync.
With the second and the third one, you must
be able to differentiate them by looking at
the response.
Because you will get some response from the
server and you must determine which request
did the server respond to.
In this case, let's say for the robots.txt
request, we expect 200 OK response code and
for the /assets/ we expect 403 Forbidden.
The value of the Content-Length header of
the first request must be between the second
and the third request.
If you count the characters, there are 24
in the first line, 4 in the second line, and
the new line is actually two bytes, one for
the carriage return and one for the actual
new line, which gives us 30.
When you send this, you should get two responses.
If everything works fine, the server will
see the first request with this one as a body,
which ends exactly between requests.
So this would be our second request.
So for the first one you expect a redirect,
and for the second one you expect the response
to the /assets/ request, which means you expect
the 403.
If that's is the case, it means you did not
find client side desync vulnerability.
However, if the server assumes the Content-Length
of the first request to be zero, you will
also get two responses.
But the second one will be the response to
the robots.txt request.
The server will also see a strange looking
header, but it's nothing out of line.
If that's the case, you are very likely that
you just found a browser powered desync.
To confirm this, you can use this perfectly
valid fetch call.
In fact, if you prefer, you can simply start
testing without using Burp but with this fetch
call.
What will happen under the hood is the browser
will send this, thinking it's a one big HTTP request.
The server, however, will ignore the Content-Length
header.
It will send two responses over the same connection.
The second one will be left hanging.
So the browser will match the first response
to the first request, as it should, and will
want to follow the redirect.
So it will send another request over the same
connection.
And in this connection, there are already
two responses.
So the browser will simply return the second
response to the request.
Let's see how we could turn this client-side
desync into an XSS on Akamai websites.
Like every client side bug, client-side desync
thing is executed from the victim's browser,
which means that we need to prepare our malicious
website with malicious JavaScript code and
trick the victim into visiting our website.
This is the setup that we want to achieve
in our connection.
The first request is our initial, vulnerable
one.
The second one is a request to which the server
will respond with text/html, Content-Type
and this response must have a Content-Length,
header, even though it's a response to a head
request so it won't have a body.
The third request will also contain an XSS
payload in a path, which will be reflected
in the response header.
Normally, this is not the problem and it's
not exploitable, so it shouldn't be that hard
to find.
And at this point, the browser will think
that it only sent one request while there
are three responses in the same connection.
So the fourth request sent by the browser will
be poisoned by headers from the second response
and headers from the third one will be the
body of the response.
So we want to make sure that this fourth request
will not be just a fetch call, but it will
be a top-level navigation so that the XSS
payload executes in the victim's browser.
But normally, the first request will return
a 301 so the fourth request would be the browser
following this redirect as a fetch call.
To prevent this, we use mode:'cors' which
will cause the browser to throw an error and
not follow this redirect.
And instead, in the catch block, will use
the top-level navigation to redirect the
victim to a new website which will be poisoned
with our headers and our body.
And the last problem is that if these two
responses are left hanging for too long, the
browser will just discard them.
So we add the cache buster parameter to the
head request so that it's processed a little
bit longer to prevent this.
So this is the final exploit that, if sent
from victim's browser, would result in an XSS
If my video helped you to understand client-side
desync, I'm very happy and I'm proud of you
because I know this is not easy.
However, this video did not cover the whole
research and I will write about some other
parts of it in next week's BBRE Premium.
If you are not a member of BBRE Premium, go
to https://bbre.dev/premium and subscribe.
For now, thank you for watching and goodbye!